oscars.org 2019-12-01

# Privacy | Oscars.org | Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences

**Effective Date: 5/21/2018**

**PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy applies to, and only to, personal information collected through **oscars.org (the “Site”)**.

The Academy of Motion Picture Arts and Sciences (“we” or “us”), the operator of the Site, is dedicated to preserving the privacy of personal information given to us by users of the Site.  A link to this Privacy Policy is set out in the footer information carried on every page of the Site.  Maintaining the privacy of user personal information is important to us, and informing our users of the types of information we collect, and how we treat it, is critical to our operation.  When you provide your personal information to us through the Site, that constitutes your agreement to the terms of this Privacy Policy. 

**_What types of personal information do   we collect from you through the Site? _** _ _  
We collect your name (first name, last name and/or full name), IP address, e-mail address and postal code when you sign up for event or Oscar Insider information.  (An IP address is a unique number that identifies your device when you are using the Internet).  We capture your name and credit card information when you purchase event tickets.

We may also capture your locational information, information about the sites you visited immediately before and immediately after you visited the Site, and the parts of the Site that you access.  In addition to personal information, the Site collects certain non-personal information, such, for example, as the type of operating system and browser you are using when you connect to the Site. 

**_How do we use the information you provide?  _** _ _  
We use the information you provide to do a better job of informing you about the Academy and Academy events and analyzing statistics.  When you join a mailing list, we ask you to provide personal information that is necessary to contact you or send you information, which includes the types of information described above. Your credit card information will be temporarily stored on a server intended to be secure, and will be used solely to process your transaction.  We will then retain your information to facilitate servicing you in the future.

**_With what types of third parties do we share your information?_**  
The personal information you provide to us is accessible only by us, except as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy.  We share your personal information with several third parties that we have hired to gather email addresses for those interested in learning more about the Academy and to process tickets. We may use cookies (small data files deposited on your hard drive) which can make it easier for you to use the Site, and to personalize your experience.  Cookies cannot read other data from your hard drive, nor can they read data from other cookies that may reside on your hard drive.  If you are concerned about the use of cookies, you may wish to learn about the features in your browser that permit it to notify you whenever a cookie is deposited, or allow you to reject cookies entirely. While most features of the Site will function properly without cookies, there may be some degradation in your experience if you reject cookies.  For that reason, we suggest that you not reject cookies.

We also use web beacons (a sometimes-transparent pixel-size graphic image on your monitor, also known as a GIF or a pixel tag) to monitor user behavior.  Web beacons can be used to identify which parts of the Site you have visited.  Neither cookies nor web beacons contain any personal information about you.  We can use cookies and web beacons to analyze traffic on the Site, to improve content and navigation, to enhance marketing, to personalize your experience.  In the future we may use web beacons to provide online display advertising, and/or offline advertising, tailored to your interests based on your online behavior, and/or share your personal information with non-profit organizations or art institutions we believe to be reputable.  Also, we use your data, aggregated with that of others, to determine usage numbers for the Site and its donor form.

Finally, we share your information when we believe we have a legal obligation to do so. 

**_Does the Site employ any third parties to collect your personal information across time and space?_** _ _  
We engage third-party vendors to help us operate the Site, process your transactions, respond to your needs, and enhance our marketing.  In managing these matters, the Site works with third-party analytics and marketing partners who use cookies and web beacons on our behalf.  We believe each of these partners to be reputable and capable.    These partners include third-party analytics vendors such as Google Analytics, and others, who serve advertisements tailored to your interests on our behalf.  They may use information about your visits to the Site and other sites to personalize ads.  We and these partners use this analytics data for several purposes, such as to improve the design and content of the Site, to inform us about such matters as which pages are most attractive to visitors, what promotions are most attractive to users, and how successful our advertising is.  As indicated above, we employ a partner to determine the site you visited immediately before and immediately after visiting the Site.  We use that visitation data only in the aggregate to understand where our traffic is coming from and where it goes.

If you are interested in learning about the use of this information, and about advertising tailored to your interests by third parties, or how to opt out of it, you can visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>, or <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices> (for users in the US or Canada), or [http://www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) (for users in Europe).

**_How do we respond to Do-Not-Track requests?_**  
The Site does not respond to a browser's "Do Not Track" signal.

**_How do you change any incorrect personal information we may have about you?_**  
Contact us at the e-mail address set forth at the end of this Privacy Policy.

**_How will you know if this Privacy Policy changes so as to become materially less restrictive?  _** _ _  
The effective date of the current Privacy Policy is posted at its beginning.  We may modify this Privacy Policy at any time, from time to time, without notice.  Modifications may be occasioned by changes in the services offered through the Site, changes in the law, changes in our internal decision-making process, or by other factors.  Each such modification will be effective immediately upon posting the revised policy on the Site.  You may wish to visit the policy from time to time to review the most recent version.  If you have not visited the site since the effective date of the current Privacy Policy, then the policy has changed to become materially less restrictive since your last visit.  **In that event, your continued use of the Site will constitute your agreement to the terms of the new Privacy Policy with regard to all personal information that you have submitted or will submit to the Site.**

**_Direct Marketing by Third Parties_**  
Subject to certain exceptions, without cost you can obtain information about, or you can stop, the transfer to third parties for use in direct marketing, of any personal information you gave us through the Site.  You can do so by using the contact information at the end of this Privacy Policy.

**_Does this Privacy Policy cover websites linked to the Site?  _** _ _  
You may find on the Site links to other websites.  We believe these transferee websites are operated by reputable organizations, but we have no control over them and cannot be held responsible for their conduct.  Accordingly, this Privacy Policy does not apply to these linked websites.  In using such websites, you should read their privacy policies and terms of use.

**_Contact Information:_** _ _  
You can contact us concerning any matter described above, or for any other questions or comments regarding the privacy of your personal information that we collect through the Site, at [privacy@oscars.org](mailto:privacy@oscars.org).
